(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
エンドロールは終わらない
Endroll Never Ends
作詞・作曲：瀬名航
Lyrics/Composition: Wataru Sena
扉の向こう繋いで
Connecting beyond the door,
生まれたはずの世界は
the world that was supposed to be born...
思いよりずっと難しくて
Is much harder than I thought,
夢がこぼれてた
and my dreams were spilling out.
伝えたいことなんて
Because there aren't many things
いくつもありはしないから
I want to say,
儚く脆い僕の声は
my fleeting and fragile voice
かすれてゆきそうだ
seems to be fading away.
三度目のなんとかだって
Even for the third time or whatever,
続ける意味を探して
searching for the meaning to continue,
未開拓だった旅の先
ahead of the unexplored journey,
これでいいと
saying "this is fine",
よかったとそう言えるまで
until I can say "I'm glad I did it".
このまま終われば誰かの美談として
If it ends like this, will it be
消費されていくでしょうか
consumed as someone's beautiful story?
ずっと後悔ばかり思い出す日々を
Now is the time to laugh,
背負って笑う今だ
carrying the days of remembering only regrets.
そんな悲しい顔をしないできっと
Don't make such a sad face,
間違ってないから
I'm sure it's not a mistake.
間違いになんて絶対に
I will never
しないよ
let it become a mistake.
すれ違いのひとつふたつだって
I spent my time trying not to care
気にしないように過ごしてた
about one or two misunderstandings.
哀さの宿ったこの身体
Because I loved this body
愛してたから
where sadness dwelt.
何者にもなれなくて
Along with the time I spent struggling
もがき続けた時間ごと
because I couldn't become anyone,
肯定できるか分からない
I don't know if I can affirm it,
分からないけど
I don't know, but...
辛ければ辛いほど
The harder it is,
笑い話にもなるでしょう
the more it will become a funny story, right?
君の声だって聞こえるから
Because I can hear your voice too,
大丈夫だよ　大丈夫だよ
It's okay, it's okay.
最高な日も　最悪な日も
On the best days, and the worst days too,
いざ三千里 これが生き様だと呼べるなら
If I can call this way of life a journey of three thousand miles...
目的地なんてない 僕らは生きている
There's no destination, but we are alive.
何度願い 何度滲み
How many times have I wished, how many times have I wept,
何度怒り 何度嘘をついてしまったんだ
how many times have I been angry, and how many times have I lied?
こんな見窄らしくて 恥ずかしくて
So shabby and shameful...
真面目すぎる僕を 隠さずに晒すよ
I'll expose my overly serious self without hiding.
ずっと誰にも言えないこの気持ちを
These feelings I've never been able to tell anyone...
吐き出してしまいたい
I want to spit them all out.
君を傷つけてしまって
I ended up hurting you.
初めて夢を描いた時から
Since the time I first envisioned a dream,
もう何年経った？
how many years have passed?
気づいたらみんな いなくなっていた
Before I knew it, everyone was gone.
僕らは出会いと別れを繰り返していく
We keep repeating encounters and partings.
ただ時間が過ぎて 終わりが来る
Time simply passes, and the end comes.
これでいい 後悔は後は自分で決めるだけだ
This is fine. I'll decide my regrets for myself.
綺麗で歪な想い出を歌にしよう
Let's turn beautiful and distorted memories into a song.
何回でも そう何回でも届けよう
No matter how many times, yes, no matter how many times, I'll deliver it.
嗚呼...
Ah...
藍彩 - Aisai - / AZKi
指をすり抜けて
Slipping through my fingers...
作詞・作曲・編曲：Keeno
Lyrics, Music, Arrangement: Keeno
やっと君を閉じ込めたのに
Even though I finally managed to lock you away.
繰り返してる呼吸に混ざって
Mixing with my repetitive breaths,
少しずつ零れてしまいそうで
it feels like it's about to spill out bit by bit.
いっそこのまま 誰にも届かない
I'd rather just, as I am now, unreachable by anyone,
深い夜の底で息を止めて
hold my breath at the bottom of the deep night...
しまいたい
...and end it all.
どくん、どくんと 涙の代わりに
Thump, thump... instead of tears,
悲しくなるほど 音立てる心臓
my heart beats so loudly it makes me sad.
分かっているの 分かっているのだけど
I know. I know, but...
まだこんなにも 君をただこんなにも
still so much, I just, so much for you...
口を噤んで 膝を抱えて
With my mouth shut, holding my knees,
そろそろ泣いてもいいですか
is it okay if I cry soon?
繰り返す幕の 行き着く先まで
Until the very end of these repeating acts,
私の全部に君がいた
you were in everything of mine.
もう二度と君に 触れられないこんな
If this is a body that can never...
身体なら意味はなくて
...touch you again, it has no meaning.
今すぐにでも脱ぎ捨てて
I want to cast it off right now...
しまいたいのに
...and be done with it, but...
もがいてもどうしようもなくて
no matter how I struggle, it's hopeless.
酷く膿んだこの傷を 掻き毟っている
I'm scratching at this terribly festered wound.
いっそこのまま 私にはいらない
I'd rather just, as I am now, I don't need it.
暗い夜の底で息をしてる
I'm breathing at the bottom of the dark night.
明日なんて このまま泣いて
Forget about tomorrow; if I just keep crying like this...
全部溢れたら 君を知らない
...and everything overflows, will I be able to become...
私になれるのかな
...a version of myself that doesn't know you?
どくん、どくんと 涙が枯れても
Thump, thump... even if my tears run dry,
この身体中を 巡る焼けるような赤
this burning red circulates through my body.
分かっているの 分かっているのだけど
I know. I know, but...
これじゃあまりにも この恋があまりにも
This is just too much. This love is just too much.
まだこんなにも 君をただこんなにも
Still so much, I just, so much for you...
はい、ということで！
Alright, everyone!
みなさん、こあずきー！
Hello everyone!
はい、本日は Route AZKi
Thank you so much for coming to the
3D Acoustic LIVEにお越しいただきありがとうございます！
Route AZKi 3D Acoustic Live today!
今日は右手にマイク、左手に地図。
Mic in the right hand, map in the left hand.
あなたのハートにゼロゲスト！
Zero Guest in your heart!
ということで、よろしくお願いします！
And with that, let's get started!
本日、お誕生日ガール、バースデーガールでございます。
Today, I'm the birthday girl.
こちらのライブはですね、AZKiのアルバム
This live stream is to celebrate
「Route If」を記念したライブとなりますので、
the release of my album, 'Route If',
本日のハッシュタグはこちら、
so please support me using the hashtag,
「#ルートAZKiライブ」でぜひぜひ応援してくださったら
#RouteAZKiLive (#ルートAZKiライブ).
とっても嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします！
I'd be so happy. Thank you!
わあ、たくさんおめでとう、ありがとう！
Wow, so many happy birthdays! Thank you!
いやあ、いい誕生日を迎えられます。ありがとうございます。
I'm having a great birthday. Thank you so much.
そして、本日ですね、アコースティックライブということで、
Since this is an acoustic live performance,
生演奏、生歌唱でお届けしていくわけなんですが、
we're bringing you live music and vocals today.
本日演奏していただきますお二人を紹介したいと思います。
I'd like to introduce the two musicians playing with me today.
まず、アコースティックギター、芦野さん！
First, on acoustic guitar, Ashino-san!
そして、ピアノ、いといさん！
And on piano, Itoi-san!
ありがとうございます。ということで、このお二人の演奏とともに
Thank you. Along with their performance,
本日アコースティックライブを...
we'll be doing this acoustic live...
いっぱいね、究極の究極をやっていきたいと思います！よろしくお願いします！
giving it our absolute best! Please enjoy!
そしてね、本日最初にお届けした曲は
The first songs we performed today were
「エンドロールは終わらない」と「藍深く」を
'Endroll wa Owaranai' and 'Ai Fukaku',
お送りしました。AZKiのオリジナル曲ですね。
AZKi's original songs. How did you like them?
今日はそのいつもとちょっと違う雰囲気でお聞きいただけると思うので、
They have a slightly different feel than usual today,
ぜひぜひ最後まで見てほしいなと思います。
so I hope you'll watch until the very end.
嬉しい告知もたくさんありますので、よろしくお願いします！
I have many exciting announcements, so stay tuned!
はい。ということでこの後はね、ちょっと衣装チェンジしたり
Next, I'll be changing my outfit,
ステージ移動したりするんですけど、
and moving to a different stage.
まね、7月。7月に入りましたね。
It's finally July. July has begun.
ということでこの後は、色んなちょっと夏にまつわる
So after this, I'll be performing
曲を皆さんにお届けしていこうと思いますので、
a variety of summer-themed songs.
ぜひぜひしっとりと聞いていっていただけたらなと思います。
I hope you enjoy this mellow section.
それでは、次の曲。お聞きください。
Now, please listen to our next song.
「夜明けと蛍」。
“Dawn and Fireflies.”
夜明けと蛍
作詞作曲 n-buna
Dawn and Fireflies
Lyrics & Composition: n-buna
淡い月に見とれてしまうから
Because I get entranced by the pale moon
暗い足元も見えずに
Without even being able to see my feet in the dark
転んだことに気がつけないまま
Without even noticing that I've fallen
遠い夜の星が滲む
The distant night stars begin to blur
したいことが見つけられないから
Because I can't find anything I want to do
急いだふり　俯くまま
I pretend to be in a hurry, head held down
転んだあとに笑われてるのも
That I'm being laughed at after falling down
気づかないで
Please don't notice...
形のない
With formless...
歌で朝を描いたまま
...songs, while painting the morning,
浅い浅い夏の向こうに
beyond the shallow, shallow summer,
冷たくない君の手のひらが見えた
I saw your hand, and it wasn't cold.
淡い空明けの蛍
A firefly in the pale morning sky.
自分勝手な幸せに怯えるほど
As much as I fear a selfish happiness,
嫌いなものが増えたので
the things I dislike have grown,
地球の裏側へ飛びたいのだ
so I want to fly to the other side of the Earth.
無人の駅に届くまで
Until I reach an unmanned station.
昨日の僕に出会うまで
Until I meet the me of yesterday.
胸が痛いから下を向くたびに
Every time I look down because my chest hurts,
君がまた遠くへ行くんだ
you go further away again.
夢を見たい僕らを汚せ
Soil us, who want to dream.
さらば昨日の夜に咲く火の花
Farewell, the flowers of fire blooming in yesterday's night.
水に映る花を 花を見ていた
I was looking at the flowers reflected in the water.
水に霞む月を 月を見ていた
I was looking at the moon hazy in the water.
から
Because...
夏が来ないままの空を描いたなら
if I painted a sky where summer never comes,
君は僕を笑うだろうか
would you laugh at me?
明け方の夢を被る月が見えた
I saw the moon wearing a dream of dawn.
空
The sky.
朝が来ないままで息ができたなら
If I could breathe without the morning ever coming,
遠い遠い夏の向こうへ
beyond the far, far summer,
冷たくない君の手のひらが見えた
I saw your hand, and it wasn't cold.
淡い朝焼けの夜空
The night sky in the pale dawn.
夏が来ないままの街を今
Right now, through the city where summer never comes,
藍の夜明けと蛍
the indigo dawn and fireflies.
もう忘れてしまったかな 夏の木陰に座ったまま
I wonder if you've already forgotten, sitting in the shade,
花に亡霊
Ghost in a Flower
作詞作曲 n-buna
Written and Composed by n-buna
アイスを口に放り込んで 風を待っていた
popping ice cream into our mouths and waiting for the wind.
もう忘れてしまったかな 世の中の全部嘘だらけ
I wonder if you've already forgotten, the world full of lies,
本当の価値を二人で探しに行こうと笑ったこと
and how we laughed, saying let's find the true value together.
忘れないように
So that I don't forget.
色褪せないように
So that it doesn't fade.
形に残るものが全てじゃないように
So that things with form aren't everything.
言葉をもっと教えて 夏が来るって教えて
Teach me more words, tell me that summer is coming.
僕は描いてる 眼に映ったのは夏の亡霊だ
I'm painting it; what was in my eyes was the ghost of summer.
風にスカートが揺れて 思い出なんて忘れて
With the skirt swaying in the wind, forget the memories.
浅い呼吸をする 汗を拭う
Taking shallow breaths, wiping away the sweat.
もう忘れてしまったかな　夏の木陰に座った頃
Have you forgotten already? When we sat in the summer shade.
遠くの丘から顔出した雲があったじゃないか
There was a cloud peeking out from the distant hill, remember?
君はそれを捕もうとして　馬鹿みたいに空を切った手で
You tried to catch it, your hand cutting through the air like a fool.
僕は髪に雲をひとつ描いて　笑って握ってみせて
I drew a cloud in your hair, smiled, and showed you I was holding it.
忘れないように
So as not to forget,
色褪せないように
So as not to let it fade,
歴史に残るものがすべてじゃないから
Because things that remain in history aren't everything.
今だけ顔をなくして
Just for now, let's lose our faces,
言葉も全部忘れて
And forget all our words.
君は笑ってる
You are laughing.
夏を待っている僕らを置いて
Leaving us behind as we wait for summer.
心をもっと教えて
Tell me more about your heart.
夏の匂いを教えて
Tell me about the scent of summer.
浅い呼吸をする
Taking shallow breaths.
うーふーふー
Ooh-hoo-hoo
忘れないように
So as not to forget,
色褪せないように
So as not to let it fade,
心に響くものがすべてじゃないから
Because things that resonate in the heart aren't everything.
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words.
さよならだって教えて
Tell me even about saying goodbye.
今を見るんだよ
Look at the "now".
夏に咲いてる花に僕らを置いて
Leaving us among the flowers blooming in summer.
言葉じゃなくて時間を
Not words, but time.
時間じゃなくて心を
Not time, but the heart.
浅い呼吸をする
Taking shallow breaths.
汗をぬぐって夏めく
Wiping away sweat, it feels like summer.
夏の匂いがする
It smells of summer.
もう忘れてしまったかな　夏の木陰に座ったまま
Have you forgotten already? While sitting in the summer shade.
アイスを口に放り込んで
Tossing an ice cream into my mouth,
風を待っていた
I was waiting for the wind.
変わらないもの
Unchanging Things
作詞作曲 奥華子
Lyrics/Composition: Hanako Oku
帰り道ふざけて歩いた
We walked home, fooling around.
訳もなく君を怒らせた
I made you angry for no reason.
いろんな君の顔を見たかったんだ
I just wanted to see all your different faces.
大きな瞳が
Those large eyes,
泣きそうな声が
That voice about to cry,
今も僕の胸を締め付ける
They still tighten my chest even now.
すれ違う人の中で
Among the people passing by,
君を追いかけた
I chased after you.
変わらないもの探していた
I was searching for things that don't change.
あの日の君を忘れはしない
I will never forget you on that day.
時を越えてく思いがある
There are feelings that transcend time.
僕は今すぐ君に会いたい
I want to see you right now.
街灯にぶら下げた思い
Feelings hung from the streetlights,
いつも君に渡せなかった
I could never give them to you.
夜は僕たちをもっと避けていたね
The night avoided us even more, didn't it?
見えない心で
With an invisible heart,
嘘ついた声が
The voice that told lies...
今も僕の胸に響いている
...is still echoing in my chest.
彷徨う時の流れの中で
In the wandering flow of time,
君と恋をした
I fell in love with you.
変わらないもの 探していた
I was searching for something that doesn't change,
あの日見つけた 知らない場所へ
to that unknown place we found that day.
君と二人で 行けるのなら
If I can go with you,
僕は何度でも生まれ変われる
I could be reborn over and over again.
形ないもの 抱きしめていた
I was holding onto something formless,
壊れる音も 聞こえないまま
without even hearing the sound of it breaking.
君と歩いた 同じ道に
On the same path I walked with you,
今も灯りは 照らし続ける
the lights still continue to shine.
変わらないもの 探していた
I was searching for something that doesn't change,
あの日の君を 忘れはしない
I won't forget you as you were that day.
時を越えていく 思いがある
There are feelings that transcend time,
僕は今すぐ君に会いたい
I want to see you right now.
はい、ありがとうございました！
Yes, thank you very much!
ということで、えー衣装も ドレス衣装にチェンジして
And with that, I've changed into a dress,
そしてね、ステージも変わりまして ちょっと夜の古庭園のステージに参りました
and the stage has also changed to this night garden.
ちょっとアコースティックな感じで
It's got a bit of an acoustic feel,
いいですよね、いいですよね？
which is nice, isn't it? Right?
ということで、「夜明けとホタル」「花に亡霊」「変わらないもの」をお送りいたしました
I've just performed "Yoake to Hotaru," "Hana ni Bourei," and "Kawaranaimono."
いつもと全く雰囲気が違って どうですか？
The atmosphere is completely different from usual. How is it?
アコースティックライブは 楽しんでいただけておりますでしょうか？
Are you all enjoying this acoustic live?
わー、ありがとうございます！
Wow, thank you!
はい、そんなわけでちょっと水分補給もしつつ
All right, well, I'll take a quick water break while...
水分補給に素晴らしいな、演奏が
The performance while I'm hydrating is wonderful...
聞こえておりますけれど、はい
...as we can all hear. Yes.
ということで、引き続き
Anyway, moving right along,
えー、夏の曲をお届けしていきたいと思います
I'd like to continue with some summer songs.
最高です。ありがとう。
That's great. Thank you.
BGM、水飲みBGMが
The BGM—the water-drinking BGM—
ありがたいですね。ゴージャスな。
is much appreciated. So gorgeous.
ゴージャスなBGMありがとうございました。
Thank you for the gorgeous BGM.
では、続きの曲に参りたいと思います。
Now, I'd like to move on to the next song.
それでは、次の曲お聴きください。 「secret base ～君がくれたもの～」
So, please listen to the next song: "secret base ~Kimi ga Kureta Mono~"
secret base ～君がくれたもの～
secret base ~Kimi ga Kureta Mono~
君と夏の終わり
With you at the end of summer,
将来の夢
dreams of the future,
大きな希望 忘れない
and great hopes—I won't forget.
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを信じて
Believe that we can meet again in August, ten years from now
最高の思い出を…
The best memories...
出会いは ふとした瞬間
Our meeting was an unexpected moment
帰り道の交差点で
At the intersection on the way home
声をかけてくれたね
You called out to me
「一緒に帰ろう」
“Let's go home together”
僕は 照れくさそうに
I, looking embarrassed,
カバンで顔を隠しながら
hiding my face with my bag
本当はとてもとても嬉しかったよ
was actually very, very happy
あぁ 花火が夜空 きれいに咲いて ちょっと切なく
Ah, the fireworks bloomed beautifully in the night sky, making me a bit sentimental
あぁ 風が時間とともに流れる
Ah, the wind flows together with time
嬉しくて 楽しくて
Happy and fun,
冒険も いろいろしたね
we went on many adventures
二人の 秘密の基地の中
Inside our secret base
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢
With you at the end of summer, our future dreams
大きな希望 忘れない
And big hopes, I won't forget them
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを信じて
Believe that we can meet again in August, ten years from now
君が最後まで 心から
That you, until the very end, from your heart,
「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと 知ってたよ
shouted “Thank you,” I knew that
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさよなら
Holding back tears, saying goodbye with a smile
せつないよね
It's painful, isn't it?
最高の思い出を…
The best memories...
あぁ 夏休みも あと少しで終わっちゃうから
Ah, because summer vacation is almost over
あぁ 太陽と月が仲よくして
Ah, let the sun and moon get along
悲しくて 寂しくて
Sad and lonely,
喧嘩も いろいろしたね
we had many fights
二人の 秘密の基地の中
Inside our secret base
君が最後まで 心から
That you, until the very end, from your heart,
「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと 知ってたよ
shouted “Thank you,” I knew that
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさよなら
Holding back tears, saying goodbye with a smile
せつないよね
It's painful, isn't it?
最高の思い出を…
The best memories...
突然の…
A sudden...
転校で…
transfer...
どうしようもなく…
powerless...
手紙書くよ 電話もするよ
I'll write letters, I'll call you too
忘れないでね 僕のことを
Don't forget me
いつまでも 二人の基地の中
Forever, inside our base
君と夏の終わり ずっと話して
At the end of summer with you, we talked on and on
夕日を見てから 星を眺め
Watching the sunset, then gazing at the stars
君の頬を流れた涙は ずっと忘れない
I'll never forget the tears that flowed down your cheeks
君が最後まで 大きく手を
That you, until the very end, waved your hand widely
振ってくれたこと きっと忘れない
to me, I'm sure I won't forget that
だからこうして 夢の中で ずっと永遠に…
So, just like this, in my dreams, forever and ever...
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢
With you at the end of summer, our future dreams
大きな希望 忘れない
And big hopes, I won't forget them
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを信じて
Believe that we can meet again in August, ten years from now
君が最後まで 心から
That you, until the very end, from your heart,
「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと 知ってたよ
shouted “Thank you,” I knew that
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさよなら
Holding back tears, saying goodbye with a smile
せつないよね
It's painful, isn't it?
最高の思い出を…
The best memories...
いつもどおりの ある日のこと
Just like always, on a certain day
君の知らない物語
The Story You Don't Know
君は突然 立ち上がり言った
You suddenly stood up and said
作詞作曲：ryo
Lyrics & Composition: ryo
「今夜 星を見に行こう」
“Tonight, let's go see the stars”
君の知らない物語
The Story You Don't Know
「たまにはいいこと言うんだね」なんてみんなして言って笑った
"You say something good for once," everyone said and laughed
明かりもない道を
On the path with no lights
バカみたいにはしゃいで歩いた
We walked and frolicked like fools
抱え込んだ孤独や不安に押しつぶされないように
So that we wouldn't be crushed by the loneliness and anxiety we held
真っ暗な世界から見上げて
Looking up from a pitch-black world
夜空は星が降るようで　いつからだろう君のことを
The night sky looked like stars were falling; I wonder since when it was...
追いかける私がいた
...that I was chasing after you
どうかお願い　驚かないで聞いてよ
Please, I beg you, don't be surprised and listen
私のこの想いを
To these feelings of mine
「あれがデネブ、アルタイル、ベガ」
"That's Deneb, Altair, and Vega"
君は指さす夏の大三角　覚えて空を見る
You point out the Summer Triangle; I look at the sky to remember
やっと見つけた織姫様
I finally found Orihime-sama
だけどどこだろう彦星様　これじゃひとりぼっち
But where is Hikoboshi-sama? I'm all alone like this
楽しげなひとつ隣の君
You're right next to me, looking happy
私は何も言えなくて
And I couldn't say a thing
本当はずっと君のことを
In truth, I always... about you...
どこかでわかっていた　見つかったって
...knew somewhere inside; even if I found you...
届きはしない　だめだよ
...it won't reach; it's no good...
泣かないで　そう言い聞かせた
..."don't cry," I told myself
強がる私は臆病で
Putting on a brave face, I was a coward
興味がないようなふりをしてた　だけど
Pretending to have no interest, but...
胸を刺す痛みは増してく
The pain piercing my chest keeps growing
ああそうか　好きになるってこういうことなんだね
Ah, I see, falling in love is a thing like this, isn't it?
どうしたい？言ってごらん
What do you want to do? Go ahead and say it
心の声がする
My heart's voice calls out
君の隣がいい
I want to be by your side
真実はお残酷だ
The truth is cruel
言わなかった
I didn't say it
言えなかった
I couldn't say it
二度と戻れない
I can never go back
あの夏の日
That summer day...
きらめく星
...the twinkling stars...
今でも思い出せるよ
I can still remember them now
笑った顔も
Your laughing face...
怒った顔も
...your angry face...
大好きでした
I loved them all
おかしいよね　わかってたのに
It's strange, isn't it? Even though I knew...
君の知らない　私だけの秘密
My secret alone, that you don't know
夜を越えて
Crossing the night...
遠い思い出の君が指をさす
...you in my distant memories point your finger...
無邪気な声で
...with an innocent voice
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
ということで、えー、secret base ～君がくれたもの～
...And so, "secret base ~Kimi ga Kureta Mono~"...
そして、君の知らない物語を2曲お届けいたしました。
...and "Kimi no Shiranai Monogatari", I've performed these two songs.
ということで、もう後半戦に入っております。
And so, we've already moved into the second half of the show.
ということで、今日のアコースティックライブ...
And so, this acoustic live today...
...「いいな！」って思ってくれたそこのあなた！
...for those of you who thought, "This is great!"
そして今日ね、アルバムリリースということで、
And since the album is being released today,
アルバムとライブの情報をちょっとおさらいしたいと思います！
I'd like to go over the information for the album and the live show!
ということで、まずはアルバム情報おさらい！はい！
So, first, let's review the album information! Here it is!
2024.07.24リリース AZKi メジャー 1st アルバム「Route If」
2024.07.24 release, AZKi Major 1st Album "Route If"
2024年7月24日水曜日リリース、
On Wednesday, July 24, 2024,
AZKiメジャー1stアルバム「Route If」がリリースされます！
AZKi's 1st major album "Route If" will be released!
よろしくお願いします！
Please check it out!
わあ！ありがとうございます！
Wow! Thank you!
こちら通常盤で、全11曲ですね、収録した...
This is the standard edition, featuring 11 tracks in total...
...初のビクターエンタテインメントさんに所属させていただいてからの...
...my first album since joining Victor Entertainment...
...初めてのアルバムが出ますので、ぜひぜひ...
...and it's coming out soon, so please...
いろんな、いろんなですね、声の温度の曲が入っておりますので、
...it contains songs with many different vocal tones,
ぜひこちら「Route If」というもしもの道をここに詰め込みましたということで、
so please check out "Route If", where I've packed various "what if" paths into this album!
こちらよろしくお願いします！
Please check it out!
通常盤はこちらで、
That's the standard edition,
そして初回限定盤にはなんと...
and in the limited first edition, amazingly...
アコースティックアレンジのDISC 2が入って、
there's a DISC 2 with acoustic arrangements,
なんと4曲もアコースティックアレンジで聴けますということで、
so you can listen to as many as four songs in acoustic style,
こちらもよろしくお願いします！
please check this out too!
そしてそして！この夏、AZKiワンマンライブ開催します！
And also! This summer, AZKi will be holding a one-man live show!
あ、ありがとうございます！
Oh, thank you!
2024年8月3日土曜日開催、
It'll be held on Saturday, August 3, 2024,
KT Zepp Yokohamaにてメジャーデビューライブ...
at KT Zepp Yokohama. My major debut live...
...「コワイロエントロピー」が開催されることになりました！
... "Kowairo Entropy" will be taking place!
今日ね、初めてAZKiのライブとかアコースティックライブ今回見て、
If you're seeing an AZKi live or acoustic live for the first time today,
「いいな」と思ってくださいましたら、
...and thought it was good,
ぜひぜひ現地でお待ちしておりますので、
I'll be waiting for you at the venue,
こちらもよろしくお願いします！
so please come!
現地チケットの情報はこちら！
Here's the ticket information!
現在、3次先行の抽選が受付中でございます！
The third round of pre-sale lottery applications is currently open!
6月29日から7月7日までとなりますのでよろしくお願いします！
It's from June 29th to July 7th, so please take note!
現地には行けないけど見たいなと思ってくださっているそんなあなたには、
For those of you who can't make it to the venue but still want to see it,
配信チケットもございますので！
there are also streaming tickets available!
こちらグッズ付きはソールドアウトしているんですが、
The ones with goods are sold out,
配信チケットございますので、
but streaming tickets are still available,
ぜひぜひこちらもよろしくお願いします！
so please check those out too!
そしてスケジュールはこちら！
And here's the schedule!
現在、3次先行の会場チケット申し込み受付しておりますので、
We're currently accepting applications for the third round of venue ticket pre-sales.
概要欄にもございますので、ぜひぜひ気になった方は申し込みいただけたらなと思います！
The link is in the description, so if you're interested, please apply!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you!
はい。
Yes.
ということで今日は、そう、バースデーガールAZKiの誕生日もたくさんお祝いいただきました！
And so today, that's right, I've also received many birthday wishes as the birthday girl AZKi!
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you so much!
はい、そんなわけで本日は、アルバムリリース記念ライブということで、
Well then, since today is a live show celebrating the album release,
本日アルバムの中から1曲...
I'm going to perform one song from the album today...
超超超最速で、新曲を1曲お披露目したいと思いまーす！
...super, super, super early! I'd like to premiere one new song!
一体何の曲が来るのか、
I wonder what song it will be.
何の曲でしょう？
What could it be?
10曲、11曲目はね、あの「いのち」の2024年版がありますけれども、はい。
The 10th and 11th tracks... well, the 11th is the 2024 version of "Inochi"...
今回ですね、披露させていただくのは、えー、AZKiの大好きな大好きなあの...
The song I'll be performing this time... it's a song written and composed by someone AZKi loves very much...
...やなぎなぎさんに作詞作曲いただきました曲をお届けしたいと思います！
...Nagi Yanagi!
お届けしたいと思いまーす！
I'd like to perform it!
では、
Well then,
次の曲お聞きください。
please listen to the next song.
map in the cup。
"map in the cup".
揺らしたティーカップ　波紋は空を泳ぎ
In a tea cup I shook, the ripples swim through the sky
角砂糖が溶けて　甘い雨を降らす
A sugar cube dissolves, and makes it rain sweet
あぁ　遠くで光ってるのは　星じゃなくて　街灯かり
Ah, what shines in the distance are streetlights, not stars
起きた 手に入れた紅茶
Woke up and made some tea
朝の光 お砂糖代わりに
Morning light, instead of sugar
浮かべて 揺らす
Floating and swaying
今日が始まるわ
Today is beginning
ちょっと特別
A little bit special
そんな気持ちになるんだ
That's how I feel
あたたまったミルク
Warmed-up milk
ほっとすれば カップ中に
Relaxing, and inside the cup
地図みたいに広がる
It spreads out like a map
ミニチュアの秘密の世界旅行
A miniature secret world tour
なんてね ゆっくり
Just kidding, taking it slowly
飲み干して
Drinking it all up
午後を迎えに行こうか
Let's go welcome the afternoon
少し読み進めた本
A book I've read a bit of
降る花びら 栞の代わりに
Falling petals, instead of a bookmark
挟んで きっと
Pressed inside, surely
次に開いたら
Next time I open it
その香りで 物語が変わってる
The story will have changed with that scent
オレンジが滲む
Orange bleeds through
水面に やまない
On the water surface, unending
花の雨が波紋を
A rain of flowers creating ripples
作ってる 自然の1ページ
Making a page of nature
めくったら 新しい
If I turn it, a new
季節かな
Season, perhaps
君と迎えに行こうか
Let's go welcome it with you
どんな毎日も ずっと
No matter what every day is like
先の自分の話だったから
Because it was always a story of my future self
特別を集めて
Gathering special things
大きな束にしたいんだ
I want to make a big bundle
一緒にね おやすみの前には
Together, before saying goodnight
ホットワイン 三日月のスパイス
Hot wine, spice of the crescent moon
一振り 心を
A dash, my heart
温めて
Warming up
星空見上げれば
If I look up at the starry sky
どこまでも 飛び立つ
Flying off to wherever
無限大の秘密の宇宙旅行
An infinite secret space tour
なんてね ゆっくり
Just kidding, slowly
夢を見て
Dreaming
明日を迎えに行こうか
Let's go welcome tomorrow
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
ということで、新曲いかがでしたでしょうか。
So, how did you like the new song?
こちらね、先ほどもお伝えしましたが、
As I mentioned earlier,
AZKiの大好きな、大好きなアーティストである
it was created by an artist AZKi loves very much,
やなぎなぎさんに作っていただいた曲になります。
the one and only Yanagi Nagi-san.
「map in the cup」なんて、
With "map in the cup"...
なんかもうすごくAZKiのね、こう好きな、
it has so many motifs that AZKi likes,
特にこの一年はいろんな変化があったんですけど、
especially with all the changes this past year,
地図のモチーフとかもたくさん入れてくださって、
she included things like the map motif,
すごく、すごく素敵な曲になりました！
and it turned into a really, really wonderful song!
ということで、こちらの楽曲「map in the cup」に関する告知があります。どうぞ！
So, I have an announcement regarding this song, "map in the cup". Here it is!
温めたミルク
Warm milk
落とせば
When I pour it
カップ中に地図みたいに広がる
It spreads inside the cup like a map
ミニチュアの秘密の世界旅行
A miniature secret world tour
なんてね
Just kidding
ゆっくり飲み干して
Drink it all up slowly
午後を迎えにいこうか
Shall we go welcome the afternoon?
はいということで、map in the cup こちらですね
So, about "map in the cup"...
アルバムリリース前の7月17日水曜日0時から先行配信決定いたしました
It's been decided that it'll be pre-released on Wednesday, July 17th, at midnight, before the album release!
そして今ねちょっと流れたMVも公開予定でございますので
And the MV that was just playing will also be released.
ちょっと一足先にみんなにアルバムの曲をお届けできればと思いまして
I wanted to deliver the album's songs to everyone a little bit early.
こちらアルバムリリース1週間前の7月17日水曜日に先行配信が決定いたしました
So, it's been decided that it'll be pre-released on Wednesday, July 17th, one week before the album release.
よろしくお願いします
I look forward to it.
MVも可愛く、イラストも可愛く仕上げておりますので、ぜひよろしくお願いしますということで
The MV is cute, and the illustrations are also cute, so please look forward to it.
皆さんお待たせいたしました
Everyone, thank you for waiting.
本日、AZKiの誕生日。こちらもございます！ドーン
Today is AZKi's birthday. And we have this too! Boom!
AZKi誕生日記念2024グッズ出ます！イエーイ
AZKi Birthday Commemoration 2024 goods are coming out! Yay!
ありがとうございます。ありますよということで
Thank you. Yes, we have them.
7月1日にやっぱグッズを出したいということで誕生日記念グッズ用意してまいりました
I really wanted to release goods on July 1st, so I've prepared these birthday commemorative goods.
ということで一つ一つ見ていきましょう
So, let's take a look at them one by one.
こちらがね、なんと、ももしき先生描き下ろしのイラストとなっております。可愛い
This is an illustration drawn by Momoshiki-sensei. So cute.
今回ね、このテーマなんですけれども「あずきんちでゆっくり」をテーマに
This time, the theme is "Relaxing at AZKi's House".
お家でリラックスできるアイテムを考えました。どうどうどう？可愛い可愛い可愛い
I thought of items that you can relax with at home. How is it? Cute, right?
ということでグッズを一つずつ紹介していきたいと思います。まずはこちらですね
So, I'd like to introduce the goods one by one. First is this.
あずきんちアクリルジオラマスタンド。可愛い
The "AZKi's House Acrylic Diorama Stand". Cute.
開拓者もおるよ。はい。開拓者が1、2、3
There's a Pioneer too. Yes, 1, 2, 3 Pioneers.
開拓者とAZKiがお家でまったりしている、ゆっくり過ごしている1日を書いてもらいました。可愛い
I had it drawn showing a Pioneer and AZKi relaxing and spending a day at home. Cute.
そして次、ランダムラバーキーホルダー
And next, the random rubber keychains.
こちらですね、串からす先生のファンアートでございます
These are fan art by Kushikarasu-sensei.
AZKiのあずきちのシリーズが可愛くてですね、なんと今回のために新しく描き下ろしいただきました
The AZKi series is so cute, and they've been newly drawn for this occasion.
なんと小豆を使ったお菓子に扮したあずきちに注目です。可愛い
Look at Azukichi dressed up as sweets made with red beans. Cute.
どれ当たっても嬉しいな。あの全部揃えたいけど、ランダムですが
I'd be happy with any of them. I want to collect them all, but it's random.
ぜひぜひこちらも、よろしくお願いします
Please, check these out as well.
そして次、あずきちとおそろいパーカーということでパーカー作りました
And next, the "Matching Hoodie with Azukichi". I made a hoodie.
アクリルジオラマスタンドのイラストで着ているAZKiとおそろっちの、おそろっちのデザインになってますよ
It's a matching design with what AZKi is wearing in the acrylic diorama stand illustration.
わー嬉しい
Wow, I'm happy.
そしてよく見てくださいよ。このデザインを
And please take a close look at this design.
なんと、胸の、このなんだ、胸元のデザインが
The design on the chest area...
なんとAZKiの文字がマップになっているんですよ。マップになってて
The letters for "AZKi" form a map! It's a map.
まぁそこにGUESSと。GUESSと書いてある
And it says "GUESS" there.
そしてこのね、持ち手のとこがなんとゲスターピンになっています
And the zipper pull is a Guester pin!
ピンになっています。可愛い。細かいところにも大変こだわりました
It's a pin. Cute. I paid a lot of attention to the details.
そして袖のデザインが「AZKi」ってなってて、あとね
The sleeve design says "AZKi", and also...
フードの下、バックのところ見ていただくとわかるんですけど
If you look at the back under the hood...
フードの下になんと開拓者が隠れてるんですね。これはね
There's a Pioneer hidden under the hood. This...
ちょっとここに開拓者忍ばせたいと思って。めちゃくちゃおしゃれな
I wanted to hide a Pioneer here. It's a very stylish...
普段も使えるパーカーをデザインしていただきました
hoodie that can be used every day.
ということで、ゆったり着れるフリーサイズとなっておりますので
It's a one-size-fits-all that you can wear loosely.
ぜひぜひこちらゲットしてください
So please, get one for yourself.
そう、開拓者をゲスしてください
Yes, please 'GUESS' the Pioneer.
ジオラマスタンドのイラストとおそろっちデザインでございます。
It has a matching design with the diorama stand illustration.
なんとカップを上から...上から覗きますと...
And if you look into the cup from above...
ピンがあるではないですか！ということで、
There's Ping! So,
表も裏もデザインして、開拓者がいて、
both the front and back are designed with pioneers,
全部飲み干したらば...あの底の下にピンがあるということで、
and when you finish your drink, Ping is there at the bottom.
あとは開拓者のシルエットデザインとなっております。
It also features a silhouette design of the pioneers.
はい、そして次。こちらはボイスということで、
Alright, next. This is the voice product.
シチュエーションボイスが発売されます。このね、
A situation voice will be released. This...
「あずきんちでゆっくりしよ」っていうテーマを、
under the theme of "Let's relax at Azukichi's place",
開拓者の君とゆっくり過ごすシチュエーションボイスになっております。
is a situation voice about spending a relaxing time with you, the pioneer.
こちらもぜひぜひよろしくお願いしますということで、
Please look forward to this as well.
誕生日記念フルセットはこちら！
Here is the Birthday Anniversary Full Set!
はい、こちらの1、2、3、4、5点ですね。と、
Yes, these five items. And,
このフルセットをなんと買っていただきましたらば、
if you purchase this full set,
チェキ風ブロマイドカードと特典ボイス、こちらが付きます。嬉しい！
you'll get a cheki-style bromide card and a special voice. I'm so happy!
ということで、直筆メッセージ書きます！
So, I'll be writing handwritten messages!
あずき直筆メッセージやったことがなくて、今回、
I've never done handwritten messages before, and this time,
フルセット全員！全員に！フルセット買ってくださった皆様に、
to everyone! To everyone who bought the full set,
直筆メッセージを書かせていただきますので、
I will be writing handwritten messages.
ぜひぜひこの初の直筆メッセージという機会なので、
Since this is my first time writing them,
ぜひフルセット購入いただけたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you could purchase the full set.
直筆メッセージの他に、箔押しの複製サイン入りの、
In addition to the handwritten message, there's also the
チェキ風ブロマイドカードも付いてきますので、お見逃しなく！
foil-stamped replica signed bromide card, so don't miss it!
そして特典ボイスも付いてきますので、こちらもよろしくお願いします。
And a bonus voice is also included, so please check it out.
はい、そしてもう一つ告知させてください。こちら！
Yes, and let me make one more announcement. This!
ドドン！AZKi 2018-2019 オリジナルソングス、
Ta-da! AZKi 2018-2019 Original Songs,
楽曲紹介ショート毎日投稿します。明日から！
I'll post song introduction Shorts every day. Starting tomorrow!
明日から20日まで、最近AZKiを知ってくださった方向けに、
From tomorrow until the 20th, for those who recently discovered AZKi,
AZKiの過去のオリジナル楽曲を紹介する試みとなっております。
I'll be introducing my past original songs.
ちゃんとAZKiがね、紹介ボイスも入れているので、
I've even recorded introduction voices for them,
毎日更新していくのでショート、TikTok、ぜひぜひ見てみてください。
so check out the Shorts and TikTok, updated daily.
ライブもあと1ヶ月後と迫っているのので、これを機会にね、
With the live concert coming up in a month, use this chance to...
そう、めちゃくちゃ用意してきたので、頑張っていろいろ用意している。ので、
I've prepared a lot. I'm working hard on many things. So,
このオリジナル曲をさらっておけば...ね。結構前になっちゃうんですけど、
if you review these original songs... though they're quite old,
前の曲もチェックできるということで、よろしくお願いします。
you can catch up on them. Thank you!
はい、そして最後。このあと本編終了後に、
Yes, and lastly. After this main performance ends,
メンバーシップアンコールライブがございます！
there will be a membership encore live!
開始は21時15分頃予定しておりますので、ぜひぜひ、
It's scheduled to start around 21:15, so please come.
こちらもよろしくお願いします。今日のライブ良かったなって思ってくださった方は、
Check it out! If you enjoyed today's live,
メンバーになっていただけたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you joined the membership.
なんとアルバムの曲がさらに聞けちゃうかも、ということで、
You might get to hear even more songs from the album,
よろしくお願いします！
so please join in!
いや〜告知モリモリ盛りだくさんということで、
Whew, that was a lot of announcements.
グッズも、そしてアルバムも、ライブもぜひぜひよろしくお願いします。
Please look forward to the merch, the album, and the live concert.
ということで、9曲目の、9曲目、
And now, for the 9th song, the 9th song,
本編最後の曲になります。
the final song of the main performance.
あ、ちょっとお水を飲みまして...
Ah, let me drink some water...
水BGMありがとうございます。
Thank you for the water BGM.
はい、ということで本日最後の曲をお届けしたいと思います。
Alright, I'd like to perform the last song of the day.
それではお聞きください。「いのち (2024 ver.)」
Please listen. "Inochi (2024 ver.)"
息をしている だから生きている
I'm breathing, so I'm alive
何度もずっと 言葉を尽くしてきたんだ
Time and time again, I've used up all my words
息をしている 野暮に見えてる
I'm breathing, it looks unrefined
青が染み出す 私にとっては何かな
Blue seeps out, what is it to me?
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heart is thumping
ここはいつも変わらずに
Here, it's always the same
活きし続けるボタンひとつの
Continuing to live, with a single button
いのち
Life
最後まで私のこと覚えてくれるの？
Will you remember me until the end?
消えてしまいそうなの 分かって
I feel like I'm about to disappear, please understand
分かってよ
Understand me...
...understand me.
ねえ 本当 本当はどうなの
Hey, tell me, how is it really?
いずれは卒業をするんでしょ
You'll eventually graduate, right?
日常に戻ったら
When you return to your daily life...
私は いなくなるの
...I will disappear.
命のような夢を見てる
I'm having a dream like a life.
またね バイバイ
See you again, bye-bye.
息を吸ってる
I'm breathing...
だから生きてる
...so I'm alive.
見た目と中身の境界線をまたいで戻って
Crossing the boundary between appearance and essence, then back again.
音が止まって
When the sound stops...
動かなくなって
...and everything stops moving.
そんな私も君は笑ってくれるかな
I wonder if you will smile for me even then.
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heart is throbbing.
ここはいつも必ずに
Here, always, without fail...
巡り続ける気分次第の命
...life continues to circulate, depending on the mood.
最後まで私のこと見届けてくれるの
Will you see me through to the end?
すがってしまいそうなの
I feel like I'm about to cling to you.
分かってよ
Understand me...
分かってよ ねえ
...understand me, hey.
真実を繋いだらもう二度と戻せないのに
Even though once truths are connected, they can never be undone.
君が忘れちゃったら私は いなくなるの
If you forget me, I will disappear.
命のような夢を見てる
I'm having a dream like a life.
またね バイバイ
See you again, bye-bye.
生き急いだあの日を軽く弄らないであげて
Please don't toy lightly with those days spent in a rush to live.
それが生きる糧になるかな
I wonder if that will become nourishment for living.
大丈夫 ずっと私は歌い続けるから
It's okay, because I will always keep on singing.
最後まで私も生きてるか分からないけど
I don't know if I'll even be alive until the end, but...
君がくれた言葉は確かに残ってる
...the words you gave me are certainly remaining.
最後まで私のこと覚えていなくてもいいから
It's fine if you don't remember me until the end.
いつ死んでしまうだろう 分かんない 分かんないよ
When will I die? I don't know, I don't know.
でも 今君が笑えたこと それだけで意味があることを
But the fact that you could smile now, that in itself has meaning...
君が忘れちゃっても私は死なないから
...so even if you forget, I will not die.
命のような夢を見てるよ
I'm having a dream like a life.
またね バイバイ
See you again, bye-bye.
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
今日は Route AZKi のライブに 来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to the Route AZKi live today!
この Route を歩むことができて よかったんだと思える。
I can feel that it was good to have been able to walk this Route.
みんなのおかげだよ！
It's all thanks to everyone!
これからも一緒に開拓していこうね。 AZKi
Let's continue to pioneer together from now on. AZKi
今日は Route AZKiのライブに 来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to Route AZKi's live today!
このRouteを歩むことができて よかったんだと思える。
I'm glad I was able to walk this Route.
みんなのおかげだよ！
It's all thanks to everyone!
これからも一緒に開拓していこうね。
Let's continue to pioneer together.
AZKi♡